Margaret Macaranas

webcrafterinc.com — macci@webcrafterinc.com / +63 906 518 5085 / Philippines

PROFILE

Hello, I'm Macci.

I have the well-rounded experience of building websites for 10 years: from planning & design, to development, to deployment & maintenance.

I love building websites. I enjoy mastering coding technologies that provide websites with seamless user experience.

I have a strong design background making Front-End Development my strongest suit.

It's my pleasure to share with your team the skills and knowledge acquired from years of experience.

SKILL SET

Front-End Web Development

Technologies used:

- HTML5, CSS3
- JavaScript, PHP
- Bootstrap, SASS
- jQuery, AJAX
- Vue.js, ReactJS
- WordPress
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Laravel
- FTP, CPanel
- Software Development Life Cycle: Development, Test, Deploy
- GitHub, Gitlab, Gulp
- Adobe Suite (XD, Photoshop, Illustrator), Figma, Sketch,

Soft Skills

Self-direction and Communication Skills

Project Planning and Management

Digital Marketing (Branding, SEO, Online Ads, Universal Marketing Concepts)

Web Design and UI/UX

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trickle Front-End Web Developer

Beautiful Company GmbH | Trickle.app | Dec 2019 - Current

With a team of fellow developers, we built Trickle.app, a curated online learning platform that helps users establish a lifelong learning habit.

Web Development

- Develop features using technologies such as Javascript, Vue.JS, AJAX, PHP, and ¡Query
- Replicate Figma UI/UX layouts to deliver responsive, engaging user experience
- Ensured code quality through debugging and testing
- Studied new web technologies to expand features, refine code, and improve processes producing smoother operations

Collaboration and Communication

- Worked closely with Trickle team to resolve issues and accelerate work flow
- Used Github to version control



< ♡ /> Freelance Web Developer & Designer

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019

Developed and managed client websites, as well as their digital marketing. Aligned development and marketing with business goals.

Web Development

- Designed and developed visually appealing, user-friendly, and well structured websites for businesses.
- Customized functionalities with CSS, JavaScript, and PHP for Wordpress, Ensured all features are running, e.g. e-commerce capabilities, customized dashboards, animation, SEO-optimization.
- Perform testing and troubleshooting. Deployed websites on hosting platforms (FTP, cPanel). Ensured regular backup.

Management and Leadership

 Explored client goals and structured deliverables & timelines accordingly. Constant communication with clients. Managed and clarified client expectations. Delegated and directed outsourced talents to finish project on time.

Creativity and Communication

- Oversaw branding and digital marketing. Designed brand complete visual and messaging identities.
- Authored and implemented marketing plans. Improved businesses' online presence on all social media, ads (social media ads and Google Adwords), directories, and of course the website. Grew brand's website traffic and social media following with ads and consistent fresh content.

EDUCATION

Bachelor / College EducationUniversity of Santo Tomas

College of Fine Arts and Design
- Major in Advertising Arts

Key Educational Achievements

- Dean's Lister (2007, 2008, 2009)
- Active member of Thomasian Writer's Guild (The university's official creative writing organization)

Secondary Education

St. Paul University, Quezon City

EXTENDED EDUCATION

Zuitt Coding Bootcamp

(Formerly Tuitt)

3-Month Intensive Full-Stack Web
 Development Training

Philippine Center for Creative Imaging

- Beginnning PHP, Apache, & MySQL
- JavaScript & jQuery for Web Interactivity
- CSS Advanced Techniques and Topics

First Academy of Computer Arts

- Rich Media Design
- Web Authoring & Integration
- Web Interface Design

Inventive Media

- WordPress CMS

...Continuation from previous page



Digital Marketing Manager

Gambit Technologies | WordPress Plugin Company | Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Directed the company's marketing program. Authored market research (user demographic, behaviour, and persona; competition or market map; industry trends). Directed over-all branding — visual identity and communication strategy. Orchestrated and delivered day-to-day online campaigns, as well as campaigns for product launches, promotions, etc. Handled social media, ads, analytics, and email marketing. Improved project planning and management in office culture.



Digital Programs Lead (Web Developer)

ASPACE Philippines | Leading Coworking in Philippines | Jan 2016 - Sep 2017

Led the management and evolution of all digital channels especially all websites under ASPACE. Oversaw programs to integrate online and anything offline.

Website Development, Maintenance, and Growth

- Developed and maintained the website using WordPress (Front-end, Back-end, and Admin).
 Ensure website achieves business objectives, is on brand, and meet UX standards. Monitored website performance. Resolved all techical issues.
- Set up procedures participated by the team to ensure all information on website is consistent and up-to-date in all 4 branches.
- Introduced systems that allow customers to seamlessly book/buy products, find all public events, register to events, make payments, apply for promos, chat with live support, etc.
- Secured top ranking with SEO practices.

Systems & Processes

- Researched, studied , and enforced new technologies to benefit the company such as: Checkfront, Capsule CRM, NinjaForms, Event Espresso, MailChimp, Zapier, etc.
- Harmonized $\,$ softwares to work together. Integrated online services to the website. Trained all team members of usage and best practices.

Branding & Marketing

- Implemented and tracked all online campaigns including the mechanics, distribution, and traffic. Participated heavily in brand's communications strategy.
- Made the website available for use even for the more complicated marketing campaigns (ex: 25%-off first 5 buyers, 10%-off first 20 buyers, and so on).

Community

- Deployed booking system for wide variations of venues/products (office space, event venues, etc). The booking system is customizable depending on the space's time capacity, allowing users to book for as low as 20 mins to as much as 6 months.
- Enforced registration system to handle small events to complicated international conferences both free and/or paid.
- Organized and hosted regular tech community meet-up: HackerNest Manila.



Senior UX/UI Designer

RMDC | Integrated Digital Marketing Firm | Nov 2014 - Dec 2015

Directed all designs for function and aesthetics of client's websites, both on desktop and on mobile. Collaborated with developers and writers to create intuitive, user-friendly websites. Redesigned and extended client's branding. Designed material for client's social media persence, ads, and content.

...Continued on next page



Senior Web Designer

MetroDeal.com | #1 Group-buying Website in Philippines | Dec 2011 - Mar 2014

Designed all online materials including interface of e-commerce website. Designed mobile application. Facilitated all marketing and branding materials such as daily promotions and online ad campaigns (Facebook Ads, Google Ads).



Web & Design Specialist

Barefoot Investments / Little Green Hub | Serviced Office | Aug 2010 - Nov 2011

Oversaw company branding and collaterals for web and print. Coordinated with client and delegated to third party talents. Managed client accounts. Conceptualized campaigns, marketing materials, including websites and online ads.

FFATURED PROJECTS

For more projects, feel free to visit my portfolio: webcrafterinc.com

THINC

WordPress, Slider Revolution

theinhouseco.com — The website is developed and designed to playfully combine elegance with latest UX trends. We also showcase the sectors our lawyers specialise and the benefit of choosing this Dubai-based law firm.

The website is heavily SEO-optimized.

Phoenix Publishing House

WordPress

<u>phoenix.com.ph</u> — Designed with strong emphasis on the company's values: Alagang Mahalaga.

The website acts as a directory of hundreds of books by the publication. Each book's details can be customized by the team from the content management system. Developed with a team.

Website also features a members-only section for teachers to access their resources.

WaveKo

WordPress, jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS

waveko.com — WaveKo is a community-minded local surf brand.

Waveko.com is a one-pager that showcases the startup's first products using product option tabs and carousel galleries. This compact website already takes in product orders.

PCIA (Philippine Concrete Industry Associated)

ReactJS, MongoDB, Express, Node, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS

 $\label{eq:philocorrete.com} {\bf philocorrete.com} - {\sf PCIA} \ {\sf is} \ {\sf a} \ {\sf network} \ {\sf of} \ {\sf construction} \ {\sf suppliers} \ {\sf in} \ {\sf the} \ {\sf Philippines}.$

Philconcrete.com enables potential members to register. The team admin also has their own dashboard where they can verify and edit member details.

Website also includes a members-only directory.

 $\label{prop:continuous} \mbox{Event registration is also synced with the organization's Facebook page.}$

CHARACTER REFERENCES

Cielito Cantero | cielitomcantero@gmail.com

(Supervisor / Lead Backend Developer at Beautiful Company GmbH)

Benjamin Intal | benjaminintal.com; twitter.com/bfintal (Previous Employer / CEO at Gambit Technologies)

Vetch Reyes | zinedil01@gmail.com

(Previous Supervisor / Deals Manager at Metrodeal.com)

Micah Asistores | ram.asistores@gmail.com

(Previous Supervisor / Community Lead at ASPACE Philippines)

Bernadette Dela Rosa | detdelarosa@gmail.com

(Previous Employer / CEO at RMDC)